What are we now?
Obviously, there's been a lot of innovation in the DeFi space.
When it comes to DeFi infrastructure,
what are we thinking from a scale from one to 10?
Tricky question to answer.
I think we saw an incredible proliferation
of various pieces of infrastructure in 2021 and 2022,
and there was obviously such a huge boom in the space.
Now, what we're really asking the question of is,
how can we put all of those pieces together end to end
that makes sense and provide a much better and stable
sequence of infrastructure
that gets everybody a consistent rate of return?
So, we're somewhere in the, you know,
sixes and sevens, I think,
and probably finding our way towards the eights and nines
as we see this institutional adoption
pressuring us to get better.
But you know, when talking about the pressure
from the institutional adoption or institutional users,
where do you think are the most blatant gaps
that we have right now?
Is it the UX UI experience?
You know, that the non-crypto native
is not able to use some of these high protocols?
Is it on the custody side?
You know, and how we interact with them?
Is it on the ecosystem round from Oracle's and others?
Where do you think are the biggest gaps
that need to be addressed?
A lot of the challenges that we see are primarily
in and around just the accounting and understanding
the management of NAV across different yield protocols,
understanding how that reflects
into more institutional balance sheet,
tax management, custody profiles.
Those are the areas that we're still trying to figure out
at scale.
They work well in small pockets,
but not quite well enough across larger infrastructure
and more sophisticated financial partners.
So you mentioned, let's say, NAV
and all these functions that we have in traditional finance,
we have the fund administrator,
we have the auditors,
and this is obviously a whole suite of service providers
that have been around for a while.
But do you believe that institutional allocators
would be comfortable with having these functions on chains?
Or a lot of them like the tried and tested,
you know, solutions and providers that we have
with centralized players, of course?
I think when you look at the proliferation of ETFs,
particularly over the last year or so,
you see a willingness to participate within digital assets,
but is that really what we consider
native on-chain asset deployment and/or asset management?
I don't think so.
It's generalized exposure to the underlying asset itself,
but is it participating within the ecosystem
and getting what I think is the best rate of return
out of playing within the sandbox of DeFi?
Not really.
That's going to change as we see the market
become more and more efficient
and effectively rates can press
and look a little bit more like traditional finance returns.
People will have to go closer to the bare metal
in order to get what they need out of digital assets
in terms of generating returns.
Just, you know, from a regulatory oversight perspective as well,
traditional hedge fund managers,
ad cryptos and managers as a whole regulatory regime for them,
what's your view on DeFi?
And let's say DeFi asset management.
Do you believe it's too early?
We may kill the innovation before it really
has a chance to blossom,
or you think they should be oversight pretty early on?
I'm a big believer in regulation and creating freedom
and clarity on how people can approach these areas.
Obviously, on an absolute basis,
DeFi is a very small asset class
if we were to put it against
traditional financial instruments.
But rates of return are really interesting
when you put them on a bare numbers basis.
As we start to see depth in books increase
and an ability for institutions to put more size at work,
there are a lot of now more tried and tested mechanisms
that big institutions can drive real cash flows
back into their balance sheet.
So I think DeFi in its original state
may not be what people get the most yield from,
but as we start to see the maturation
of the stablecoin markets and money markets more broadly
and better capital efficiency
and broader open windows, 24/7 markets,
that's gonna change how we get returns.
- Let's mention capital efficiency, right?
I remember in the early days of crypto trading,
crypto platform, centralized platform,
didn't even have cross-portfolio margin.
And even if you look at now,
some of the most successful, a larger DeFi platforms,
there's, again, there's no cross-portfolio margin.
I would say the capital is not very efficient.
How do you believe that can change?
Like, what is needed to improve that
and to make it more capital efficient
and thus increase returns
and attract more institutional investors?
- Yeah, we're really asking the question
of how do we distribute risk across an ecosystem?
When you can start to handle more marginal in the system,
you need a way to distribute those risks
in structured financial instruments or derivatives
that could then be transferred
between different parties and counterparties.
There isn't any great downside protection,
insurance mechanism or risk control tool
that you can sell on as an institutional asset manager
within crypto or digital assets.
That'll be my opinion, the area which will really open this up.
If you think about the size of insurance
and reinsurance markets within traditional finance,
I'd love to find out who's building in that space
and find a way to grow that area within the ecosystem.
- And you know, when we talk about decentralized finance
and especially from an asset management angle
you're looking at, do you believe the,
let's say the DeFi asset management ecosystem
is actually properly decentralized today?
We saw following the Bybit hack,
how obviously there was a lot of, you know,
discussions around the topic.
Many were argued some of the large DeFi protocols
we have today are also not as decentralized as they should be
and some of the other yield offering platforms as well.
How do you see it from your vantage point?
- It's a great question.
There are a lot of protocols out there
that just due to the nature of distribution mechanisms
across their token and governance structures,
they kind of wander towards a decentralized practice
just by vesting and incentive mechanisms.
However, there are a lot of individual asset managers
and asset management platforms who are with no shame
or, you know, hiding of it.
They are centralized asset management platforms.
They are there to take a directional bid on the space.
Protocols themselves in the early innings of DeFi
were obviously meant to be fully decentralized.
Are they, I think there's a lot of shades of gray within that.
And that's something that I look for regulatory clarity on
in order to get a better sense for where is a safe
or sensible place to put assets at work,
knowing what the counterparty is likely to do
and how they're likely to make decisions
around direction of protocols.
- Interesting. One last quick question in 30 seconds.
Obviously, in October this year,
we had, let's say, a massive volatility in the market
and obviously a lot of challenges
with some centralized exchanges,
massive ripple effect on the DeFi world.
When we look back at what happened in October 2025,
a year from now, do you think we would have learned from this?
We'd be positive.
How do you think that impact of that event
will have on the rest of the ecosystem?
- We always say we'll learn from putting too much leverage
in the system and we always get taken back
a few steps one day every couple of years.
Yes, I think some of the slightly more irresponsible actors
around leverage and risk will get washed out.
I think we're still finding some of those parties
as the dust is still settling.
Hopefully that means that more sensible
and or less aggressive asset managers,
allocators and participants with the space
will end up taking the top seats at the table
and we can have more durable rates of return
across the market.
- Durable rate of return.
That's what we want to see.
That was very interesting actually.
Definitely I got to follow a lot of upside in that vertical.
Thank you. That was Nick Roberts.
Definitely the co-founder of Blueprint Finance.